investegate.co.uk 2019-10-25

# FE InvestEgate, Privacy policy

This Privacy Policy was updated on **22nd July, 2019**

## SUMMARY

When you register on FE Investegate we collect some personal information so that we can secure your account, and to store your portfolios. To improve the experience, we use services like Google Analytics, which collects anonymous browsing information such as the most viewed company announcements. We use cookies to serve you relevant ads and appropriate content (such as showing certain ads or research articles only to professional investors), and to provide services such as login.

We’ll only send you email alerts if you’ve asked for them – and you can stop receiving them at any time. You can control cookies using your browser settings. If you have any questions about the registration data we have on you, including to verify it is accurate please contact us (details at the bottom of this page).

## ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY

FE Investegate provides free-to-access company announcements, market and stock news to private investors.

This Privacy Policy explains how FE Investegate uses information you provide to us or that we collect about you, how we collect it and which other trusted organisations we share it with. It also tells you how you can limit the information we collect and exercise your data rights.

### Also see:

\- [FE’s Data Protection Policy](https://feorchard.blob.core.windows.net/media/Default/Policies/FE%20Data%20Protection%20Policy.pdf)

\- [FE’s Data Processing Schedule](http://www.financialexpress.net/data-processing-schedule)

\- For more information about FE please visit our [website here.](http://www.financialexpress.net/)

## ABOUT US

FE Investegate (“Investegate”, “we”, “us”, “our”, “the website”) is part of Financial Express (Holdings) Limited. You can find our contact information here. 

We may share the information we collect across our group companies and websites including but not limited to FE Analytics, financialexpress.net and Trustnet.com. 

## WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU?

#### 1\. Information that relates directly to you such as your name and email address

We collect information about you when you register with us or use the site. When you set up alerts, we ask you to register and set up a user name, your full name, your private investor status, your broad occupation, and a password. E-mail addresses are required to register for some features of the site. Occasionally we may ask you for other contact details such as a telephone number or postal address for the purpose explicitly stated on the contact form on the website

If you complete a contact form on the website we may contact you by email, phone or post, but we will only do so if you've given us your affirmative consent for each method of contact. You can change your preferences by logging into your account on the website or via the instructions that accompany each piece of communication (e.g. links to manage preferences in emails we send to you).

#### 2\. Information that does not directly identify you such as your browsing behaviour on Investegate

Through the use of cookies, we may collect data on the pages you’ve viewed, information about your computer, including where available your operating system, browser version, domain name and IP address and details of the website that you came from

We use IP address information alone to identify business usage of our service. This is done through the usage of LeadForensics technologies. Any non-business associated IP addresses (e.g. individuals’ IP addresses or dynamic IP addresses) are being discarded immediately and no longer processed by LeadForensics technologies. For retained business associated IP addresses we will directly collect metrics (visit timestamps, count of pageviews, count of visits, visit durations), and dimensions (URL viewed, device type, browser). Also for the business associated IP addresses,, through a third party, we will indirectly collect additional dimensions (company name; company registered address(es), country, county, postal code; company website address and telephone number; industry and SIC (Standard Industry Classification Code); published AUM and /or turnover (if listed); number of employees; company registration number and year of founding)

**Investegate, and any other websites, products or services from FE are not intended to collect or process special types of data such as medical or biometric data, nor any data relating to children.**

## HOW WE USE INFORMATION 

When you access the website we might store and use your information to:

  * Remember you when you visit our website and to see which company announcements, news and other pages you visit. We do this using cookies.
  * Ensure that the content we display to you is appropriate and compliant based on your level of investment knowledge.
  * Identify your interests using anonymized data. We may use this to create audience segments that we then use to serve targeted, relevant advertising to you on the website
  * Identify aggregated and anonymised browsing behaviour on the website to provide us and in some cases, 3rd parties, with insight into company or market research trends.
  * Target advertising to you based on your IP address.
  * To provide you with information by email, post or phone, products or services that you request from us, such as email newsletters or which may interest you, tailored to your specific interests, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes and by such means. This may be by or on behalf of 3rd parties but only with your explicit permission. 
  * To ensure the content we display to you on the website is done in the most appropriate and efficient way, such as by identifying the device you are using and formatting the website appropriately. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts between you and us and/or in relation to our terms and conditions;
  * To enable you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
  * To decide how to develop our products;

We may also send you emails to provide information and keep you up to date with developments on our site. It is our policy to have instructions on how to unsubscribe so that you will not receive any future e-mails. You can change your e-mail address at any time by logging into your account and updating your profile.

In order to provide support on the usage of the Investegate email alerts service, our support team need access to all information provided in relation to this.

However, you agree that we may disclose to any regulatory authority to which we are subject and to any investment exchange on which we may deal or to its related clearing house (or to investigators, inspectors or agents appointed by them), or to any person empowered to require such information by or under any legal enactment, any information they may request or require relating to you, or if relevant, any of your clients.

## HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION

When you access, register on or complete a contact form on the website, we collect information on you in the following ways:

  * directly from you – when you complete an account registration form or any other form where we ask for personal or non-personal information.
  * indirectly from you via your browsing behaviour on the website using a variety of web technologies such as cookies and other digital tracking tools.
  * we may also use personal and/or non-personal information about you that we have collected on one of our other websites or from 3rd parties such as industry or regulatory database providers. This information may have been collected in-person, by telephone, on websites or in other ways.

## YOUR PERMISSION TO BE CONTACTED

We always endeavour to provide a substantial and meaningful explanation of the scope and the purpose for which we are collecting your information at the point at which it is collected, as well as providing you with the means to freely grant, or withdraw your consent for us to collect and store your information, and to use it to contact you where applicable. 

Occasionally we may ask for your permission to share your information with 3rd parties we work with to offer you relevant information, products or services by email. This will be explained at the point at which your information and consent is collected, and your consent can be withdrawn at any time.

## ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION AND CORRECTION

We want to ensure that the personal information we hold about you is accurate and up to date. 

You can update your details, contact preferences (e.g. which companies you receive alerts about) and consent by accessing your profile on the website. Alternatively, to see what personal information we have collected from you, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove, deactivate it by emailing fedataprotection@financialexpress.net.

You have the right to access information held about you. If you wish to receive a copy of any personal information we hold, please email your request to fedataprotection@financialexpress.net. 

## WHERE AND HOW WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) in order to facilitate our use of that information as stated above. It may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers ([FE’s Appointed Sub-processors](http://www.financialexpress.net/appointed-sub-processors)). Such staff may be engaged in, amongst other things, the provision of support services. We will take all steps reasonably necessary, including the use of encryption, to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy and the General Data Protection Regulations

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is never completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone. You will not hold us responsible for any breach of security unless we have been negligent or in wilful default.

Please refer to [FE’s Appointed Sub-processors](http://www.financialexpress.net/appointed-sub-processors).

### How long do we keep your data?

We will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## COOKIES

A cookie is a small file containing a piece of information (a string of letters and numbers that acts as an identifier) that is placed on your browser when you visit certain websites. Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies

### Types of cookies we use:

When you access our site, we ask for your consent to allow us to store the following cookies on your device.

**Essential cookies:** When you register on Investegate (to set up email alerts, for example), a cookie is placed on your browser to let us know that you are signed in (or not), and your investor type (i.e. a private investor – you will be asked this at the point of registration). The registration cookie enables our servers to determine what content you can view – that which is designated to suit your requirements and complies with various licenses we hold about the type of information we can supply to different types of investor. While you are signed in we combine information from your registration cookies with analytics cookies, which we could use to identify which pages you have seen on Investegate. We use Google Tag Manager to manage many of our analytics and third-party cookies. We use CloudFlare to cache content on the website. We use CloudFlare for security and optimising the website’s performance – this requires CloudFlare to use cookies.

**Analytics cookies** anonymously remember your computer when you visit the website. They keep track of, for example, the number of visitors who browse the website, their browsing patterns, which country they are in and what devices is used to visit the website. We might use that information to target advertisements to you on our and other websites. 

**Advertising cookies** enable us to identify what types of adverts you have seen, for example so that you’re not shown the same advertisement too many times. We also use advertising cookies to help us use targeted advertising. We may use cookies set by other organisations so we can more accurately target advertising to you. These cookies are anonymous- they only collect information on what you have looked at on the website, not who you are. We may also set cookies on selected other sites that we advertise on in order to identify you (anonymously) as having visited those sites before or after you’ve visited the website so we can then target our advertising based on this information.

**Third party tracking cookies** which are placed by or on behalf of independent advertisers who are advertising on our site. These cookies may be placed within the advertisement and elsewhere on our site. They are anonymous – they cannot identify individuals. They are used for statistical analysis by allowing the advertiser to count how many people have seen their advertisement or have seen it more than once. They might also allow the advertiser to tailor advertising to you when you visit other websites.

**Other third-party cookies:** Other organisations may also set their own cookies in order to anonymously track your engagement and interaction with their products and services on the website. An example of this could be if you were to ‘follow’ Investegate on Twitter via a follow button on a company announcement, Twitter may place a cookie on your browser to measure this. We cannot access these cookies (likewise, these organisations cannot access cookies we place on your browser).

### _When you access our site, we ask for your consent to allow us to store the following cookies on your device:_

#### Analytics Cookies

Google Analytics | Twitter Analytics  
---|---  
Clicky | Google Analytics Audiences  
New Relic | Moz  

#### Advertising cookies

Doubleclick / Google  | Google Safeframe | Amazon Associates | Gumgum  
---|---|---|---  
Publisher Tag | AppNexus | Rubicon | CPX Interactive  
Google Adsense | Moat | Criteo | Dotomi  
Google Pingback | Quantcast | Tribal Fusion | Turn Inc  
Google Ad Measurement | OpenX | Advertising.com | Rocket Fuel  
PulsePoint | Flashtalking | Impression Desk | Widespace  
DoubleClick Bid Manager | Brightroll | SiteScout | RUN  
PubMatic | SMART Adserver | Delta Projects | GetIntent  
Adobe Audience Manager | SpotXchange | ConvertMedia | BidTheatre  
Netmining | Crimtan | Tapad | Yahoo Ad Manager Plus  
SkimLinks | Magnetic | Drawbridge | Rhythmone Beacon  
MediaMath | Adap.tv | Connexity | Beeswax  
Media Innovation Group | TradeDesk | Nexage  
Simpli.fi | Integral Ad Science | EQWorks  
RadiumOne | Adform | BidSwitch  

#### 3rd party tracking cookies

       Hubspot | Marketo  
---|---  
       Bluekai | SalesForce  

#### Other third-party cookies

       Facebook | Google+  
---|---  
       LinkedIn | Twitter  

## MANAGING COOKIES

Most browsers allow you to block cookies, as well as deleting existing ones. To do this look at the “help” menu on your browser. Please note though, that if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or part of our site and you will still be shown advertisements, just less relevant ones. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies as soon as you visit our site. You can also delete cookies from your browser – use your browser’s ‘help’ section for specific instructions, or visit the [‘Cookies and me’](https://cookies.insites.com/disable-cookies/) website for user-friendly instructions for most popular browsers

If you would prefer to just restrict third party cookies (or to find out more information about opting out of third party cookies), visit www.youronlinechoices.com or click on the AdChoices logo that you will see in the corner of advertisements that carry behavioural targeting cookies.

The main advertising serving system we use is DoubleClick by Google. To see what information Google collects and how you can manage it please visit https://privacy.google.com/intl/en/your-data.html 

## AD BLOCKERS

We may attempt to detect whether or not you are using an ad blocker through the use of Javascript, this will only be used to confirm that advertising is displaying correctly based on the device and browser you are using – it will not collect or store any personal information. 

We may restrict access to the website or some of its contents and features if an ad blocker is detected. Investegate relies on advertising in order to fund its research and data and enables us to do this without a charge to you. If you have an ad blocker enabled, please disable it or permit advertising on the website in your ad blocker tools settings. We aim to only run advertising that is appropriate and conforms to standards set out by the IAB and the Coalition for Better Ads initiative. If you do see advertising on the website that you think is disrupting your research, inappropriate or annoying, please try to screen capture it, or make a note of the page you are on and the brand being advertised and send it to FESupport@financialexpress.net and we will investigate with the aim of preventing it or similar adverts from displaying.

## CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

## OTHER WEBSITES

Our site contains links to other websites. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

## CONTACT

If you want more information or have any questions or comments relating to our privacy policy please contact FE’s Data Protection Officer:

Address: Data Protection Officer, FAO Sorin Pop, 3rd Floor, Hollywood House, Church Street East, Woking, Surrey, GU21 6HJ, United Kingdom

Email: [fedataprotection@financialexpress.net](mailto:fedataprotection@financialexpress.net)

Telephone: 01483-783940
